Guide to the American Service Institute Records, ca. 1920-1961 AIS.1963.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Service Institute Records
1920-1961
1941-1961
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Service Institute
AIS.1963.01
62.5 Linear Feet
The American Service Institute was founded in Pittsburgh in 1941 with the purpose of working through the organized structure of the Pittsburgh community to promote better understanding and appreciation among people of all cultural and national backgrounds. The American Service Institute was in existence from 1941 through 1961. The records include material from the 1920s through 1961. The records include minutes and committees, unpublished studies and reports, ASI community projects, immigration and naturalization files, ASI publications, ASI programs, general information on local organizations, material on local community projects, the aged population, youth immigration records, and customs and traditions of cultural groups.
History
The American Service Institute was founded in 1941 as a result of research published by Philip Klein and collaborators entitled A Social Study of Pittsburgh: Community Problems and Social Services of Allegheny County. The study recommended that an advisory agency be formed to act as an interpreter between existing social and civic agencies. The American Service Institute (ASI) was formed from the combination of 3 organizations the, International Institute of Pittsburgh, International Institute of McKeesport and the American Citizenship League. The organizations focused on a combination of naturalization procedures for individuals as well as community related group work.
The ASI was a product of the three earlier organizations with the stated purpose, "to assist in the ethnic, cultural and economic assimilation into the community of new Americans residing in Allegheny County; to encourage their participation in community life, as individuals or as groups; to cooperate with individuals and with nationality organizations in relating themselves to public and private social and civic agencies; and to give technical assistance to residents of Allegheny County who desire to become naturalized citizens of the United States." To fulfill these objectives, ASI worked through the organized structure of the community (i.e., social agencies, schools, churches, civic groups) to promote better understanding and appreciation among people of all cultural and national backgrounds, as well as encourage fuller participation in community life.
The organization was supported almost solely by the Community Chest of Allegheny County, only a fraction of the ASI budget came from fees for services. ASI did not intend for itself to be an agency that provided individual service, but in their first year they assisted 1,140 people with the naturalization process. After those initial months government funds for naturalization programs made it possible to lessen the number of individual cases for which ASI was responsible.
In 1960 a study was requested by the Community Chest of Allegheny County and the Allegheny County Health and Welfare Association to assess the role of the American Service Institute. As a result of the study the ASI was asked to terminate its services to the community and its contract with the Community Chest expired on December 31, 1961. All active immigration and naturalization case files were transferred to the Community Chest Information Services, which later became part of the Pittsburgh Chapter of the United Way.
Scope and Content Notes
Included in the collection are extensive records in the fields of social work and intercultural relations. The collection also contains publications of health, welfare, and fraternal organizations located in the county, and numerous documents and letters of historical importance. Although the American Service Institute was in existence from 1941 through 1961, the material in the files is not limited to this period but contains materials from the 1920s through 1961. The records include minutes and committees, unpublished studies and reports, ASI community projects, files on individual immigration and naturalization cases closed prior to 1953, ASI publications such as the Survey of Beneficial Fraternal Society, newsletters, Nationality Fact Sheet, ASI Programs such as "Analysis of Immigration and Naturalization Steps" and "East Liberty Interagency Meetings," general information on such local organizations as the Urban League, National Conference of Christians and Jews Committee on Human Relations, material (such as newsletters) on local community and committee projects, the aged population, youth immigration records, customs and traditions of cultural groups.
Arrangement
The collection has been organized into eight main series:
Series I. Special Projects and Daily Activities
Series II. Research on Ethnic and Nationality Groups
Series III. Alphabetical Subject Files
Series IV. Individual and Family Case Files
Series V. Employment Progress Reports
Series VI. Newsletters and Publications
Series VII. Additional ASI Files
Series VIII. Map and Statistics Binders
Additional scope notes are provided at the series level.
Access Restrictions
Repository may place some restriction on the use of individual immigration files if they are used in other than a statistical fashion.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Otto Von Mering on October 7, 1963.
Previous Citation
American Service Institute Records, ca.1920-1961, AIS.1963.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Neighborhoods -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Immigrants -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Community life; Ethnic groups; Community development; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Emigration and immigration; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Social conditions; Associations; American Service Institute; National Conference of Christians and Jews. Committee on Human Relations; Urban League of Pittsburgh
- Special Projects and Daily Activities, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I contains minutes, correspondence and research for specific projects on local and national levels. Topics include fair housing, citizenship classes, naturalization, war relief, Japanese resettlement, community profiles, and various aspects of social work. The series also includes correspondence and minutes of meetings in which the ASI participated. Organizations such as the Human Relations Institute, McKeesport Intercultural Council, Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, Urban League of Pittsburgh as well as other local organizations and settlement houses. Social work conferences held by the American Service Institute are also included in this series.
  - American By Choice, 1.
    - Rewrite material - Americans by Choice. Contributions (To American Life) Italian (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rewrite material - Americans by Choice. Italians in Pittsburgh (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rewrite material - Americans by Choice Allegheny Valley Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny Valley Service Bureau - Tarentum, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - I Am An American Day, McKeesport, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
    - I Am An American Day, McKeesport, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Tarentum Area, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny Valley Advisory Committee of the ASI, undated (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Tarentum Occupational and Industrial Survey, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tarentum Conference, April 30, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Tarentum Dubois Conference (I Am An American Day), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Study Committee-Tarentum YMCA, Group Work Division, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. Sigler's Report of Allegheny Valley, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Radio Programs, Allegheny Valley, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Radio Forum, Tarentum, May 26, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Publicity, Tarentum, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Intercultural and Inter-racial Understanding, October 18-19, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - West Deer Township-Program File (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Study Committee-Springdale Community Center (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bach, Julia, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Barkovic (Rygielski) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bartkiewicz and Markel, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bronikovsky, Ahven, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Barrett (Oleh) Julia American Orientation, August 6, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - American Orientation Committee, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - American Orientation Institute, December 1959 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - American Orientation Institute (AOI), undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - AOI, Employment Committee, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - American Orientation Institute, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Citizenship Classes Services, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Citizenship Recognition Ceremonies, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Mass Bicentennial Citizenship Ceremony, February 12, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Analysis of IN Immigration Slips to School Board, July 1955-August 1958 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Citizenship Education Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Institute on Police-Community Relations, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Pittsburgh Council on International Visitors, May 1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Anti-Defamation Project, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bicentennial Celebration (Nationality Groups), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Americanism Week, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Manchester Human Relations Workshop, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Pittsburgh Association for U.N., undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Maisel Reception Luncheon, Intercultural Understanding Day, July 19, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - East Liberty Inter-Agency Meetings, April 1959 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Finnish Visitors to Pittsburgh, March-April 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Duquesne Folk Festival Reports, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Clairton Housing Project, June 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dormont - Mt. Lebanon Citizenship Classes, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Records, interviews - Dormont Profile, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "East Liberty Study" Larimer Avenue, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - East Liberty Program ASI, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - East Liberty, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - East Liberty Community Council, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - East Liberty, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Highland Park Pool, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hill District, undated (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
    - Homewood - Brushton, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Homestead - Munhall Project, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Homestead Community Studies - Local, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Homestead, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - McKeesport, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - McKeesport Profile - Follow up, October 1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - McKeesport, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - McKees Rocks Community Organization Project, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Pittsburgh Housing Situation, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - McKees Rocks, undated (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - Rankin Community Organization Project, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Spring Hill, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - ASI Profile, 2.
    - East Liberty, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Larmer Avenue Area Profile, October 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Rankin Profile - ASI Correspondence (list), August 1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Manchester Community Profile - ASI, Correspondence, lists, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - McKeesport Valley Area Community Profile. ASI, October 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Spring Hill Profile - ASI, Correspondence, lists, June 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Penn Township Profile, June 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dormont Community Profile. ASI, 1957. Correspondence, lists (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - McKees Rocks. "Community Profiles" ASI. Correspondence, lists, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Articles Re Profiles in Pittsburgh Press - ASI, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Consultation of Camps and Miscellaneous, 3.
    - Brashear Camp, Camp Claudine Virginia Trees, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Camp Consultation, Brashear, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Consultation - training, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Camp Redwing, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - ELR'S Camp records, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Camp DVT (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Camp Carondowanna, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Camp Winnicut, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Consultation Assistance to Equitable Gas Co., undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Community School - Health Workshop, July 1957, June 1958, and July 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Consultation - ISDA - ASI - CHR "Mafia" (Articles), June 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ASI Cultural Factors Meetings, 4.
    - 1st Cultural Factors Meeting, Dr. M.H. Giles, March 30, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 2nd Cultural Factors Meeting, Dr. Kenneth Clark, March 30, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 3rd Cultural Factors Meeting, Dr. Dan Dodson, March 12, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 4th Cultural Factors Meeting, Dr. M.F. Ashley Montagu, March 28, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 5th Cultural Factors Meeting, Dr. E. Alpenfels, April 9, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Cultural Problems - Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Committee on Cultural Factors in Group Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Materials From the Study Committee on Cultural Factors in Group Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Sub-Committee on Inter-Cultural Education of the Workers' Section, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Committee on Cultural Factors in Group Work- Minutes, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Study Committee on Intercultural Education, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Case Summaries re Cultural Problems, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cultural Factors in Health, 5.
    - ASI Cultural Factors in Health Committee, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
    - Cultural Factors in Health Committee- Minutes, Agendas, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Dr. Demke - County Health Department. Nationality Leaders' Meetings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Citizenship Recognition Ceremonies, 6.
    - Citizenship Ceremony Bicentennial, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Citizenship Ceremonies, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    - Citizenship Recognition Ceremonies (miscellaneous information) Summary Report included, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - ASI - Fraternal Societies. Television Series (Americans All), Fall, 1956; 7.
    - Fraternal Society Flag Day TV Program. WQED, June 14, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Opening Show. "Americans All Series". WQED, September 6, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Croatian Program. "Americans All Series". WQED, September 13, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Slovak Program. "Americans All Series". WQED, September 27, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - German Program. "Americans All Series". WQED, October 11, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Hungarian Program. "Americans All Series". WQED, October 4, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Italian Program. "Americans All Series". WQED, October 18, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Polish Program "Americans All Series". WQED, September 20, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ukrainian Program "Americans All Series". WQED, October 25, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - TV General Meetings - Fraternal Societies of Greater Pittsburgh. Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fraternal Societies of Greater Pittsburgh, 1956. TV Series. WQED, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - ASI - Fraternal Societies. "Americans All Series", Fall, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Russian and Carpatho-Russian. "Americans All Series" WQED, November 1, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Development of Fraternalism. WQED, November 8, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Human Relations Institute, 8.
    - Human Relations Institute, February 21, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Human Relations Institute, February 25, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Human Relations Institute, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Planning Committee, Institute on Human Relations, February 17, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Human Relations Institute, Programs and Announcements (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Human Relations Institute, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Institute on Human Relations, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Human Relations Institute, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Institute on Human Relations, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Program Committee, Institute on Human Relations, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Institute on Human Relations, November 19, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Institute on Human Relations, Finances, November 19, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Institute on Human Relations, February 7, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Joint Meeting on Intercultural Education in the County Preceding, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Human Relations Institute, Statements of Purpose, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hungarian Refugee Situation, 9.
    - Hungarian Aid, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
    - Hungarian Refugees- ASI and Citizens Coordinating Committee, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Materials- Hungarian Refugees- correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Reports- Hungarian Refugees- records, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Problems of Employment- Hungarian Refugee- correspondence data project, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Hungarian Refugee Survey- completed forms, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hungarian Data, incomplete forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Hungarian Project- Work Folder, Report- Ruth Auel Interpretation by ASI, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - "The ASI," a term paper, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Purposes of American in Field of Human Relations, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Resources- Social Agencies and Organizations, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Purpose, services and origin ASI, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - ASI- Interpretive Publication, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Japanese Resettlement, 10.
    - Committee on Resettlement of the Japanese (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Materials and Bulletins re resettlement (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - Manzannar Press Items (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Pittsburgh Citizens' Committee on Resettlement (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Resettlement of Japanese, publicity (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - WRA - Intake Slips and Referrals (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Joint Cooperation, 11.
    - ASI in relation to the Urban League, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - I NS- ASI. Cooperation Board of Education, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Civic Unity Council (ASI). Origin, relation to CUC, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Meeting of representatives of Bureau of Community Councils, ASI, Urban League, Housing Authority and Feb. (By Community Chest), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - McKeesport, 12.
    - Minutes - McKeesport Advisory Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - McKeesport Home Festival, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - McKeesport Intercultural Council. BHDC, 1948-1951 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - McKeesport Intercultural Council. Program, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - McKeesport Intercultural Council, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - McKeesport Advisory Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - McKeesport Intercultural Council, Nominating and Membership Committee Records, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Community Chest of McKeesport, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - McKeesport Office - Program Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - McKees Rocks-Community Organization Project, 13.
    - McKees Rocks--Hope McDermott's Use, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - McKees Rocks, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Consultation to McKees Rocks Rotary Club, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks Mailing lists, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks c/o Project, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks English and Citizenship Classes, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Judith Ann Snyder Memorial Library, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-Rocks. Judith Ann Snyder Memorial Library, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, McKees Rocks, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks. Banquets and Ceremonies, May 1954 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks. Publicity-correspondence, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Clippings of Stowe-Kennedy-McKees Rocks, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Tri-Community Brotherhood Program Ball, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Nationality Organizations Directory, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - D.P. Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
    - Council of Churches-D.P. Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - D.P. Minutes and Charts, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Independence Day Festival Committee, 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Nationality Integration Committee-United War Fund Campaign, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Overseas Relief Agencies, 14.
    - War Relief Agencies. General Correspondence, Lists, etc., 1944-1956 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - American Relief for Czechoslovakia, Inc., 1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - British War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - China War Relief, United China War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Clothing Drive, United War Relief, January 1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Danish War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Fashion Show Luncheon Committee, Council of War Relief Agencies, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - French War Relief (Belgium), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Greek War Relief, Friends of Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Italian War Relief, American Relief for Italy, Inc., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Lithuanian War Relief, United Lithuanian Relief Fund of America, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Netherlands War Relief, Queen Wilhelmina Fund, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Norwegian War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Polish War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Russian War Relief, American Society for Russian Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Yugoslav War Relief, United Yugoslav Relief Fund, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Yugoslav War Relief, American Committee for Yugoslav War Relief, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - War Relief (Malvin Morton's Thesis), Correspondence and list, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - unidentified (II 4 18), undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - School-Community Receptions, 15.
    - Peabody School Reception (For English and citizenship classes), December 15, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Receptions with English and Citizenship classes, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - School-Community Luncheon. (Forbes School Citizenship Class), May 27, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Lawrenceville Reception for Potential Citizens, March 15, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Services to the Foreign Born - Case Work Services to Foreign Born, (includes conference with Dr. Bernard), 1958-1959; 16.
    - Services to the Foreign Born, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Transfer-Community Committees, 17.
    - Allegheny County Committee on Displaced Persons, Organization of committee, lists, correspondence, etc., 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, minutes, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Citizens Committee on Civil Rights (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - New C.U.C. Ordinance, March 1955 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Advisory Committee, Civic Unity Council, Community Committees, 1945-1955 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Mayor's Civic Unity Council (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
    - Highland Park Pool Committee, Civil Unity Council (Box 6, Folder 34)